NJUNO PETER MBURU CURRICULUM VITAE

Personal Details

Name: Peter Njuno

Address: P.O.Box 92 – 00227 Kinale – Kenya

Mobile: 0711588950

Email: mpnjuno@gmail.com, pmnjuno@gmail.com

Website: http://165.22.203.175/master/

Summary

Skilled and innovative insurance / finance officer with over 5 years of experience and familiarity with bank and transactions reconciliations, audits, journals, accounting for incoming and outgoing RTGS/TTs/SWIFT/EFTs, credit management, medical insurance underwriting, strategic planning, Quick Books, customer care, financial analysis and financial reporting. Am highly innovative, detailed oriented, sharp analytical thinker, detailed oriented, good with numbers and always meet deadlines.

Work Experience

Finance Officer Medical Division

First Assurance Kenya Limited, Jan 2015 to present. Main Responsibilities.

- Preparation of reports and financial statements to provide senior managers and staff with information for management and status of company's medical finances.
- Complete accurate statement reconciliations for 250 plus medical service providers.
- Medical department bank reconciliations.
- Preparation, posting and processing of medical agents and brokers medical commissions.
- Preparation, posting and processing of medical service providers payments and individual member reimbursements.
- Medical premiums collections, allocations, updating and sharing of statements to various clients.
- Assist in budget preparation.
- Established and maintain relationships with medical providers' representative to provide assistance with problems they may encounter.
- Assist in internal and external audits etc.

Team Leader for Loan Officers

Traders Investment Solutions – 05.01.2015 – 31.04.2015.

Main Responsibilities

- Marketing and meeting with loan applicants and collection and verification of their financial documents.
- Determining if the person or business qualified for a loan and reviewed loan agreements with them to ensure that they complied with set SLAs.
- Helping and advising customers through the application and payment period.

School Accountant

Kenton Secondary School, March – Dec 2013

Main Responsibility

- Handled collection of school fees and managing school's book of accounts.
- Tracking and management of payables and receivables.
- Assisted with day-to-day operations of the Finance department, including filing, report generation, budget review, etc.
- Preparations of invoices and school budgets.

Credit Department Intern

Consolidated Bank of Kenya Limited - 01.08.2012 - 31.10.2012.

Main Responsibilities

- Evaluating clients' credit data and financial statements in order to determine the degree of risk involved in lending money to them.
- Filling out loan applications and including the credit analysis and loan request summaries, then submitting these loan applications to loan committees for their approval
- Helped with the filing process.

Additional Skills

- Self-taught Programming, fluent in Java, C#, Python, PHP, JavaScript and web programming technologies.
- Self-taught Data Science.

Academic Qualifications

Master's In Business Administration.

Finance Option – Continuing.

Done with class work working on Project, set to graduate this year.

Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology.

Diploma in Insurance.

Currently attending classes for Module I Kenya School of Insurance

Bachelor Degree in Commerce

Banking and Finance Option -2^{nd} Class Upper Catholic University of Eastern Africa. Class of 2012.

Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education

Mean Grade B of 65 points (Top of the class). Kahawa Garrison Secondary School. Class of 2008.

Referees

Mrs Dorothy Oludhe Head of Care Team – First Assurance doludhe@firstassurance.co.ke Mob No. 0735823928

Mr Adam Nganga
Head of Medical Operations
Sanlam General Insurance
ajnganga@gmail.com, anganga@sanlam.co.ke

Mob No: 0720831671

Mr Wanjohi SW Principal – Kenton Secondary School

Mob No: 0723409012

Address: P.O.Box 61257 - 00200 Nairobi

Mr Joseph Kariuki

Lecturer - Catholic University of Eastern Africa

Mob No: 0721619266 j.kariuki@cuea.edu

Address: P.O.Box 61257 - 00200 Nairobi